### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

PhD in genetics with extensive genomics and bioinformatics experience including next-generation sequencing analysis and machine learning/deep learning expertise. 15+ years of research experience including molecular biology and genetic manipulation in numerous *in vitro* and *in vivo* systems. Expert in CRISPR-Cas systems and their therapeutic applications. Strong independent and collaborative publication record in both primary research and scientific literature reviews. Passionate about genome editing, aging biology, epigenetics, and neuroscience.

### **EDUCATION**

# Stanford University, Stanford, CA

2014 - 2020

Ph.D. in Genetics

Thesis Project: Chromatin accessibility dynamics underlie a decline in neural stem cell (NSC) migratory ability with age

### Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Cambridge, MA

2009 - 2013

Bachelor's of Science in Biological Engineering
Major: Biological Engineering, Minor: Mathematics

### **SKILLS**

Computational Languages: R, Python, PyTorch, Bash, Matlab

**Bioinformatics:** RNA-seq, ChIP-seq, ATAC-seq pipeline analysis (bowtie2, tophat, cufflinks, SAMtools, Bedtools, Picard, MACS2, DESeq2, EdgeR, deepTools, DiffBind, ChIPSeeker, Homer, NucleoATAC), scRNA-seq analysis (Seurat), long read sequencing analysis (NanoQC, Minimap2)

Machine Learning: Supervised machine learning (ElasticNet, SVM, Random Forest, XGBoost), Unsupervised machine learning (PCA, MDS, t-SNE, UMAP), Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) sampling, Deep learning (CNNs, LLMs) Molecular Biology: ATAC-seq library generation, CRISPR-Cas9 genome editing, lentiviral construction, FACS, immunofluorescence staining, tissue culture, cryosectioning, confocal microscopy, qPCR, western blots

**Mouse Animal Procedures:** Large-scale animal studies, mouse colony husbandry, brain microdissections, multi-tissue necropsies, paraformaldehyde perfusions

*C. elegans* **Animal Procedures:** Animal husbandry, lifespan assays, genetic crosses, extrachromosomal microinjections, biolistic bombardment, UV integration

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## EpiCRISPR Biotechnologies, South San Francisco, CA

June 2021-July 2024

Head of Biological Data Science Biological Data Scientist II Biological Data Scientist I

## Stanford University – Department of Genetics, Stanford, CA

July 2015-June 2021

Postdoctoral scholar with Dr. Anne Brunet Graduate student with Dr. Anne Brunet

# Harvard School of Public Health - Department of GCD, Cambridge, MA

July 2013 - July 2014

Research technician for Dr. William Mair

### MIT - Guarente Lab for the Study of Aging, Cambridge, MA

Feb 2011 - May 2013

Research Internship with Dr. Leonard Guarente

### Hôpitale Pitié-Salpêtrière Neuroepidemiology Lab, Paris, France

Summer 2012

Research Internship with Dr. Christophe Tzourio

# University of Toronto (MaRS Centre) – Rottapel Lab, Toronto, ON, Canada

Summer 2010

Research Internship with Dr. Robert Rottapel

# MIT – Laboratory for Multiscale Regenerative Technologies, Cambridge, MA

Jan – April 2010

Research Internship with Dr. Sangeeta Bhatia

### University of Toronto (MaRS Centre) – Rottapel Lab, Toronto, ON, Canada

*Nov 2008 – Sep 2009* 

Research Internship with Dr. Robert Rottapel